Soviet Union and Russia Pentecostal Subject Files, Inclusive: 1928-2006, Bulk: 1975-1983
Baylor University, The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society
Soviet Union and Russia Pentecostal Subject Files
Inclusive: 1928-2006, Bulk: 1975-1983
Baylor University, The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society http://www.baylor.edu/kestoncenter/
25
Keston Institute, 1969 -
17 A4 document boxes
The Soviet Union and Russia Pentecostal Subject Files contain a variety of materials on the Evangelical Christian Pentecostal Church and persecution of Pentecostal believers in the former Soviet Union.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Keston College, originally founded in 1969 as the Center for the Study of Religion and Communism with the named changed to Keston College in 1974, collected and publicized details about religious persecution behind the Iron Curtain, becoming “the voice of the voiceless.” After the collapse of communism in the 1990s, Keston College moved to Oxford and downsized due to decreased funding. The name eventually changed to Keston Institute. In 2007, the Institute transferred the Keston Archive and Library to the newly created Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society at Baylor University.
Keston collected, verified, translated, and disseminated information received from believers in the Soviet Union, Poland, Romania, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Yugoslavia, Bulgaria and other communist countries. The Keston Archive and Library housed numerous letters, petitions, reports and underground publications (Samizdat) from believers of various denominations along with officially published books and periodicals.
In the early 1960s, Keston began collecting materials on the persecution of Pentecostals in the Soviet Union.
Various revivals around the world, including the Welsh Revival of 1904-1905 and the Azusa Street Revival in Los Angeles that began in 1906, inspired early Pentecostal evangelists in the Russian Empire. Prior to the 1917 Revolution that toppled the czar, the Orthodox Church worked alongside authorities to persecute marginalized religions. Pentecostals, in particular, risked persecution because of their contentious relationship with other Christian faiths. Such persecution was a precursor to what Pentecostals would experience following the 1917 Revolution and later during the formal anti-religious movement in the Soviet Union.
The communist government subjected Pentecostal church members to harsh treatment, but rather than suppressing their faith, the opposite occurred. Prominent Pentecostal leader Gustav Schmidt wrote a series of articles describing revival that sprang from persecution. By 1930, more than 500 Pentecostal churches had been organized in the Soviet Union and Ukraine, largely due to the missionary zeal of the Pentecostal faith. The practitioners knew the risk of openly professing their faith but believed that the risk strengthened their relationship with Christ. Numerous Pentecostal leaders were arrested and imprisoned in Soviet labor camps where many died of malnutrition or disease before completing their sentences.
In 1945, following World War II, a majority of Pentecostal churches in the Soviet Union were forced to unite with the All-Union Council of Evangelical Christian-Baptists (AUCECB) in order to be legally recognized by state authorities. During the merger, over 25,000 Pentecostals from 400 congregations joined the AUCECB. However, many resented the forced merger and refused legal recognition. They became known as “unregistered,” and suffered greater persecution than their legally recognized brethren. In 1971, Ivan Fedotov became the first unregistered Pentecostal Russian bishop after serving 18 years in prison camps.
In the 1980’s, Mikhail Gorbachev enacted several laws regarding religion in the Soviet Union. One such law allowed emigration for religious minorities. Under the allowance, more than 350,000 Soviet Pentecostals emigrated to the United States. Many of the religious refugees continued to practice their faith in conjunction with Slavic Pentecostal unions. In spite of the migration, an estimated 1.2 million plus Pentecostals reside in the former Soviet Union today.
Scope and Content
The Soviet Union and Russia Pentecostal Subject Files contain materials about the history of the Evangelical Christian Pentecostal Church and persecution of Pentecostal believers in the Soviet Union. The files consist of newspaper clippings, bibliographic references, transcripts, reports, print materials, and various forms of Samizdat, including underground publications and unofficially circulated documents and records.
The materials cover a period from 1928 to 2006 with the bulk from 1975 to 1983. The most notable topics include, but are not limited to, the state authorities’ oppressive practices against Pentecostal Christians and the believers’ fight for their rights to conscientious objection and emigration on religious grounds. Geographically, the materials cover persecution of Pentecostal communities in Krasnodarsky Krai, the Siberian city of Chernogorsk, the Russian Far East towns of Nakhodka and Chuguevka, and the former Soviet Republics of Ukraine, Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania. Individual accounts of persecution include the cases of the Siberian Seven, two Pentecostal Christian families from Chernogorsk, who lived in the United State Embassy in Moscow from 1975 to 1983, and the situation of the Bulakh family from Vilnius, Lithuania, whose children wrote letters to President Jimmy Carter.
Some materials pertain to relations between Evangelical Christian Pentecostals and the state in post-Soviet Russia.
Arrangement
The Keston Center received most of the Soviet Union and Russia Pentecostal materials in files organized by subject. This original filing system has been largely preserved. Siberian Seven and Siberian Seven Campaign materials have been organized into a separate series and divided further into specific categories.
The Soviet Union and Russia Pentecostal Subject Files are currently arranged into three series: I. Siberian Seven Materials, II. General, and III. Samizdat
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to the Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 25.
Related Resources
Related references
Lunkin, Roman. “Traditional Pentecostals in Russia.” East-West Church and Ministry Report vol. 12, no. 3 (Summer 2004).
Rodgers, Darrin J. “Gustav Schmidt Describes the Horror of Soviet Persecution of Pentecostals in the 1930s.” Flower Pentecostal Heritage Center. August 4, 2016.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Chmykhalov, Timothy, 1962-; Perchatkin, Boris.; Vaschenko, Augustina.; Vashchenko, Lida.
Places
Soviet Union -- Church history.; Soviet Union -- Emigration and immigration.
Subjects
Baptists -- Soviet Union -- History.; Christian women -- Religious life -- Soviet Union.; Christians -- Soviet Union.; Communism and Christianity -- Soviet Union -- History.; Evangelicalism -- Soviet Union -- History.; Freedom of religion -- Soviet Union.; Government, Resistance to -- Soviet Union.; Human rights.; Hunger Strikes.; Pentecostals -- Soviet Union — Biography.; Pentecostals -- Soviet Union.; Persecution -- Soviet Union.; Protestant women -- Soviet Union.; Protestantism -- Soviet Union -- History.
Genres
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Publications.; Records (Documents); Transcripts.
- Siberian Seven Materials, 1975-1983; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  The Siberian Seven Materials series contains items pertaining to seven members of the Vashchenko and Chmykhalovs families from the Siberian city of Chernogorsk, who fled to the United States Embassy in Moscow to avoid persecution. From 1975 to 1983, the families lived in the Embassy waiting for Soviet authorities to issue permission to emigrate. The Campaign to Free the Siberian Seven was launched in the West in 1981. The crusade was organized by Danny Smith and sponsored by Buzz, the largest interdenominational Christian magazine in Great Britain. Buzz editor Peter Meadows served as chair of the campaign’s interdenominational committee.
  The materials were collected by Michael Rowe, an expert on Russian Protestants and a Keston representative on the Campaign Committee. Rowe actively participated in the Campaign and gained the trust of the Siberian Seven. Many of their original handwritten letters in the series are addressed to Michael Rowe and his family.
  The series is in good condition.
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Committee Meeting Minutes and Planning, 1981-1983, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Reports, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Press Releases (1 of 2), 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Press Releases (2 of 2), 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Letter Communications, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Correspondence: General (1 of 3), 1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Correspondence: General (2 of 3), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Correspondence: General (3 of 3), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Correspondence: TELEX Communications, 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Correspondence: French Support, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Correspondence: Christian Solidarity International, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Correspondence: Christian Solidarity International: Letters of Support to Siberian Seven, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Correspondence: Vashchenko and Chmykhalov Letters (1 of 2), 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Correspondence: Vashchenko and Chmykhalov Letters (2 of 2), 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Swedish Politicians Appeal to L. Brezhnev, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Grigorii Vashchenko Documents, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Kent Hill, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Assorted Articles, 1981-1983, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Publicity Projects, 1981, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Lidia Vashchenko Interview, 1983 April 15 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Print Materials, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Buzz Magazine Support, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Buzz Magazine Information Packet, 1981 June (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Buzz Magazine Issue, 1981 June (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Print Materials, 1981 June (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Vienna Maps, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Siberian Seven Campaign: Photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Siberian Seven: General, 1975, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Siberian Seven: British and U.S. Government Support, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Siberian Seven: Reports in Western Press (1 of 4), 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Siberian Seven: Reports in Western Press (2 of 4), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Siberian Seven: Reports in Western Press (3 of 4), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Siberian Seven: Reports in Western Press (4 of 4), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Siberian Seven: Reports in Western Press: Chmykhalov Family, 1983-1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Siberian Seven: Reports in Western Press: Vashchenko Family, 1983-1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Siberian Seven: Letters and Appeals: Chmykhalov Family, 1979, 1981-1982, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Siberian Seven: Letters and Appeals: Vashchenko Family (1 of 3), 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Siberian Seven: Letters and Appeals: Vashchenko Family (2 of 3), 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Siberian Seven: Letters and Appeals: Vashchenko Family (3 of 3), 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- General, 1960-2006; 2
  The series contains information on the history and persecution of the Evangelical Christian Pentecostal Church in the Soviet Union and oppressive practices against Pentecostal believers and their fight for the right to conscientious objection and emigration on religious grounds.
  The series in good condition.
  - Pentecostal Church. General (1 of 2), 1960-1971 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Pentecostal Church. General (2 of 2), 1971-1981, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Pentecostal Church. History. General, 1928, 1930-1982, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Individual Pentecostal Believers. General, 1962, 1976-1988 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Individual Pentecostal Believers. Barats, Vasili, Barats, Galina, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Individual Pentecostal Believers. List of Names, 1977-1979, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Pentecostal Church Administration. Individual Churches, 1962, 1984-1986, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Pentecostal Church Administration. All-Union Council of Pentecostal Churches, 1977-1980, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Pentecostal Church-State Relations, 1975-1980 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Pentecostal Church-Relations. Opening and Registration of Churches, 1958, 1971-1989, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Oppressive Practices Against Pentecostal Church. General, 1962-1963, 1974-2006, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Oppressive Practices Against Pentecostal Church. Harassment and Discrimination, 1976-1991, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Oppressive Practices Against Pentecostal Church. Physical Assault, 1977-1984 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Oppressive Practices Against Pentecostal Church. Denial of Right to Assemble, 1975-1983, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Oppressive Practices Against Pentecostal Church. Fines, 1969-1987, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Oppressive Practices Against Pentecostal Church. Interrogations, 1972-1984 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Oppressive Practices Against Pentecostal Church. Trials. General, 1961-1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Oppressive Practices Against Pentecostal Church. Imprisonment. General (1 of 2), 1969-1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Oppressive Practices Against Pentecostal Church. Imprisonment. General (2 of 2), 1984-1988 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - State Interference in the Affairs of the Pentecostal Church. General, 1979-1984 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - State Interference in the Affairs of the Pentecostal Church. Refusal to Register, 1962, 1981-1987, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Oppressive Practices Against Pentecostal Church. Maltreatment of Believers in the Army, 1976-1989, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Oppressive Practices Against Pentecostal Church. Discrimination in Employment, 1977-1982 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Oppressive Practices Against Pentecostal Church. Discrimination in Education, 1977-1984 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Oppressive Practices Against Pentecostal Church. Abuse of Psychiatry, 1974-1988 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Oppressive Practices Against Pentecostal Church. Attacks in the Media, 1962-1987, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Oppressive Practices Against Pentecostal Church. House Searches. Confiscation of Property, 1977-1986, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Oppressive Practices Against Pentecostal Church. Loss of Parental Rights, 1961-1984 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Pentecostal Church Life, 1962-1988, 1998, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Pentecostal Church. Official Publications, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Pentecostal Church. Clergy. Priesthood, 1974-1986 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Pentecostal Church. International Relations, 1976-1984, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Pentecostal Church. Contacts with International Organizations, 1977-1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Pentecostal Church. Visits from Foreign Delegations, 1977-1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Pentecostal Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. General, 1962-1983 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Pentecostal Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Public Demonstrations and Protests, 1977-1999 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Pentecostal Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Defense of Believers' Rights, 1980-1988 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Pentecostal Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Conscientious Objections, 1974-1989 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Pentecostal Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Emigration on Religious Grounds. General (1 of 6), 1974-1976 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Pentecostal Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Emigration on Religious Grounds. General (2 of 6), 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Pentecostal Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Emigration on Religious Grounds. General (3 of 6), 1979-1984 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Pentecostal Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Emigration on Religious Grounds. General (4 of 6), 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Pentecostal Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Emigration on Religious Grounds. General (5 of 6), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Pentecostal Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Emigration on Religious Grounds. General (6 of 6), 1988-1999, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Pentecostal Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Emigration on Religious Grounds. Chuguevka, 1983-1988 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Pentecostal Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Contacts with Foreigners, 1976-1982 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Pentecostal Church. Activities Disapproved by the State. Samizdat, 1975, 1979, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Pentecostal Church. Charitable Activity, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Pentecostal Church. Education. General, 1976-1981 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Pentecostal Church Unity, Schisms, and Doctrinal Differences, 1970-1980, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Pentecostal Church Statistics, 1974-1982 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Pentecostal Church. Relations with Fellow Believers, 1974-1988 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Pentecostal Church. Relations with Other Denominations, 1977-1982 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Pentecostal Church. Religion and National Identity, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Pentecostal Church. Involvement in Secular Affairs and Politics, 1977, 1981, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Pentecostal Church. Youth and Children, 1963, 1969, 1976-1982, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Pentecostal Church. Sociology and Family, 1966, 1969, 1976, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Pentecostal Church. Visual Materials, 1963, 1978, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Samizdat, 1961-1988; 3
  The series contains information on persecution of Evangelical Christian Pentecostal believers in the Soviet Union and their fight for the right to conscientious objection and emigration on religious grounds. The materials include unofficially circulated documents, testimonials, reports, letters, and appeals.
  - Pentecostal Church. History. General, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Individual Pentecostal Believers. General, 1979-1982 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Individual Pentecostal Believers. Barats Family, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Individual Pentecostal Believers. Bresenden, Evgenii, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Individual Pentecostal Believers. Panasiuk, Arsenii, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Individual Pentecostal Believers. Sidenko Family, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Individual Pentecostal Believers. Skubii Family, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Individual Pentecostal Believers. List of Names, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Pentecostal Church Statute, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Fraternal Council of Christians of Evangelical Faith - Pentecostals, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Collection of Evangelical Christian Pentecostal Documents Compiled by Stanislav Zherdev, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Pentecostal Church-State Relations, 1976, 1979, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Oppressive Practices against Pentecostal Believers. General (1 of 6), 1972-1978 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Oppressive Practices against Pentecostal Believers. General (2 of 6), 1979 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Oppressive Practices against Pentecostal Believers. General (3 of 6), 1980 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Oppressive Practices against Pentecostal Believers. General (4 of 6), 1980 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Oppressive Practices against Pentecostal Believers. General (5 of 6), 1980-1983, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Oppressive Practices against Pentecostal Believers. General (6 of 6), undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Oppressive Practices against Pentecostal Believers. Chuguevka, 1982-1986 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Oppressive Practices against Pentecostal Believers. Vilnius, Lithuania, 1976-1988 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Oppressive Practices against Pentecostal Believers. Harassment, 1978-1979, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Oppressive Practices against Pentecostal Believers. Physical Assault, 1976-1979 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Oppressive Practices against Pentecostal Believers. Disruption of Services and Meetings, 1974-1983 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Oppressive Practices against Pentecostal Believers. Disruption of Services. Maloyaroslavets Church, 1980-1982 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Oppressive Practices against Pentecostal Believers. Fines. General, 1980, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Oppressive Practices against Pentecostal Believers. Fines. Kaluga Region, 1973-1980 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Oppressive Practices against Pentecostal Believers. Fines. Maloyaroslavets Community, 1972-1984 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Oppressive Practices against Pentecostal Believers. Fines. Vinnytsa Ukraine, 1975-1979 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Oppressive Practices against Pentecostal Believers. Interrogations. General, 1974-1980, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Oppressive Practices against Pentecostal Believers. Interrogations. Maloyaroslavets Community, 1974-1981 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Pentecostal Believers Trials. General, 1961-1968, 1980, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Pentecostal Believers Trials. Akhterov, Pavel, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Pentecostal Believers Trials. Boyarovskaya, Tamara, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Pentecostal Believers Trials. Bulakh, Eduard, 1981, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Pentecostal Believers Trials. Fedotov, Ivan (1 of 3), 1961-1974 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Pentecostal Believers Trials. Fedotov, Ivan (2 of 3), 1975 January-March (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Pentecostal Believers Trials. Fedotov, Ivan (3 of 3), 1975 April (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Pentecostal Believers Trials. Fedotov, Ivan and Murashkin, Vladimir (1 of 2), 1981 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Pentecostal Believers Trials. Fedotov, Ivan and Murashkin, Vladimir (2 of 2), 1981 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Pentecostal Believers Trials. Khlevnoi, Mikhail. Nikolaevo Region, Ukraine, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Pentecostal Believers Trials. Kostiuk, Stepan and Tsimmerman, Richard, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Pentecostal Believers Trials. Walter, Viktor, 1985-1987 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Pentecostal Believers Trials. Vashchenkos, 1961-1974 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Pentecostal Believers Trials. Ukraine, 1957-1983 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Pentecostal Believers Imprisonment. General, 1982, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Pentecostal Believers Imprisonment. Fedotov, Ivan, 1974, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Pentecostal Believers Imprisonment. Goretoi, Nikolai, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Pentecostal Believers Imprisonment. Nakhodka, 1980-1983 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Pentecostal Believers Imprisonment. Shevchenko, Yuri, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 5)